# Colleen E. Cleary

(646) 422-9052 • New York, NY cleary.ce@gmail.com • https://colleencleary.github.io/

## • Full Stack Developer •

I am a passionate, driven, and curious full-stack software developer and lifelong learner with a knack for problem-solving. With my background in Physics and through my collaborative and independent computationally-based astrophysics research, I've developed a creative, yet practical approach to projects, as well as a keen eye for detail.

### **SUMMARY OF SKILLS**

Tools and Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Sass/Scss, Bootstrap, jQuery, JSON, DOM manipulation, Python (2.6/3.3), Django, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Node, Express, Angular, AJAX, React, REST API, APIs, MVC framework, Mongo, Mongoose, PostgreSQL, database/SQL, C++, Java, Git/Github, Slack, Heroku, GIMP, Inkscape, Mathematica, MATLAB, Development Tools

**Coursework**: advanced C++, Java, x86, Object-Oriented Programming, data structures, discrete mathematics, and numerical analysis, software development, web application architecture and servers, visual design and user experience

Extras: Quick learner, adaptable/flexibility, strong leader and collaborator, excellent communicator (analytical, written, and verbal)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## General Assembly Web Development Immersive Web Development Fellow

May 2018 - August 2018 New York, NY

Participated in a full-time immersive Web Development course, completing in-class projects, hackathons, and personal projects focused on real-world applications of web development principles and best practices. Developed a portfolio of individually and collaboratively focused inclass projects, including:

- Ghost-Neutralizer, an in-browser ghost-hunting game
- Women of STEM: Astronomy, a private online community for women in astronomy
- The Tipsy Tiki, an interactive tropical drink directory

### American Museum of Natural History Undergraduate Student Researcher

February 2016 - Present New York, NY

Created and developed Python algorithms for analyzing and modeling astronomical data (including high resolution cosmological simulations of black holes in dwarf galaxies, as well as brown dwarf photometry). Results presented at national conferences, as well as submitted for publication in the Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. Additionally, served as programming resource to other students.

## Midtown Comics Assistant Manager

September 2010-June 2016 New York, NY

Trained and led team of over a dozen employees at the highly trafficked Grand Central location of New York's leading comic book retail chain, personally interacting with hundreds of return customers weekly. Established store policies, objectives, and procedures, and communicated with other managers daily regarding store-related matters. Traveled as a representative for international and local conventions, and remotely recruited, trained, and managed 4-6 volunteers per event. Implemented inventory system that reduced thousands of dollars in company losses.

### NASA Goddard Institute for Space Studies Undergraduate Student Researcher

May 2015 - August 2015 New York, NY

Led team of two high school students in creating a numerical simulation of an organic lightemitting diode to analyze the output efficiency due to various combinations of optical properties. Coordinated and led group presentation at relevant conferences in the New York area.

### **EDUCATION**

Physics B.A. with minor in Mathematics (May 2018), City University of New York at Hunter College Computer Science A.S. Candidate, City University of New York at LaGuardia Community College